<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BigData101</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <string name="element_text">Element</string>
    <string name="grid_layout_manager">Grid Layout Manager</string>
    <string name="linear_layout_manager">Linear Layout Manager</string>


    <string name="intro_text">Welcome to Big Data 101. Here you will learn concerning the technological as well as the legal aspects of Big Data. We will also have a look at the new GDPR and how this will affect companies in switzerland, espacially the insurance companies. You will also learn in this part, why the GDPR is sometimes loosely formulated and why there are no simple guidelines and rules a company can implement in regareds to the GDPR, since sometimes the circumstances are way more complicated than one might think. Giving the GDPR such a strong force with high penalties if not kept can also be catastrophical.</string>
    <string name="technology_text">Lets first have a look at the definition of Big Data. Big Data simply describes a data set that is too large to be processes by commercial end-user components like laptops or mobile phones or home computers. This data might be generated by sensors which input a hughe amount of data continuously. Or it might also be that the database of your insurance company might have grown too big for just a home computer to process. Just look at the data that a service like facebook gathers and processes. And so forth. Some text here.</string>
    <string name="law_text">Lets have a closer look here at the law aspect of this whole topic. We will look first at the GDPR, what it means in regards to big data nad in regards to insurcance companies in switzerland. we will then also look if there are some speicifc swiss laws that also touch on ths subject.</string>
    <string name="combination_text">Now that we know about both fields, lets try to bring them both together, and look at espaeially the difficulties that come with it. Like we learned, it is not that easy sto simpley geographically sort the members. Blabla. The GDPR wants to bring the world data security like the USA wants to bring the world democracy. IP-blocking? But I can simply spoof IP-Addressses. etc.</string>
    <string name="introduction">Introduction</string>
    <string name="technology">Technology</string>
    <string name="law">Law</string>
    <string name="combination">Combination</string>
    <string name="big_data_101">Big Data 101</string>
    <string name="legal_disclaimer">No advice\nThis app contains general information about legal matters. The information is not advice, and should not be treated as such.\nLimitation of warranties\nThe legal information on this app is provided “as is” without any representations or warranties, express or implied. BigData101 makes no representations or warranties in relation to the legal information on this app. Without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing paragraph, BigData101 does not warrant that \nthe legal information on this app will be constantly available, or available at all; or\nthe legal information on this app is complete, true, accurate, up-to-date, or non-misleading.\nProfessional assistance\nYou must not rely on the information on this app as an alternative to legal advice from your attorney or other professional legal services provider. If you have any specific questions about any legal matter you should consult your attorney or other professional legal services provider. You should never delay seeking legal advice, disregard legal advice, or commence or discontinue any legal action because of information on this app.\nLiability\nNothing in this legal disclaimer will limit any of our liabilities in any way that is not permitted under applicable law, or exclude any of our liabilities that may not be excluded under applicable law.</string>
    <string name="accountability">accountability</string>
    <string name="data_protection_impact_assessment">data protection impact assessment</string>
    <string name="data_protection_officer">data protection officer</string>
    <string name="examples">examples</string>
    <string name="fines">fines</string>
    <string name="gdpr_principles">gdpr principles</string>
    <string name="how_and_where_data_is_stored">how and where data is stored</string>
    <string name="how_big_data_is_obtained">how big data is obtained</string>
    <string name="how_data_is_organized">how data is organized</string>
    <string name="how_dat_is_processed">how dat is processed</string>
    <string name="main_principles">main principles</string>
    <string name="privacy_by_desing_and_default">privacy by desing and default</string>
    <string name="problems_with_the_gdpr">problems with the gdpr</string>
    <string name="processor_and_controller">processor and controller</string>
    <string name="reprimands">reprimands</string>
    <string name="right_to_data_portability">right to data portability</string>
    <string name="right_to_erasure">right to erasure</string>
    <string name="security">security</string>
    <string name="terms_and_definitions">terms and definitions</string>
    <string name="theory">theory</string>
    <string name="what_is_big_data">what is big data</string>
    <string name="what_is_big_data_used_for">what is big data used for</string>
</resources>
